Alfonso Mayo Arias

Arturo Soria 110; Building 3; 3°B, 28027, Madrid, Spain

+34 652189598 | alfonsomayo@student.ie.edu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Industrial engineer with experience in two logistics procurement projects in a pharmaceutical distribution company and in a leisure company. Interested in public policies. Equipped with excellent interpersonal and organizational skills and experience working with multicultural groups. Currently undertaking a Master in International Relations.

EDUCATION

IE School of International Relations

Master in International Relations

Madrid, Spain October 2013 - July 2014

Université Libre de Bruxelles

Erasmus program

Brussels, Belgium September 2011 – September 2012

Escuela de Ingeniería y Arquitectura. Universidad de Zaragoza

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering

Zaragoza, SpainSeptember 2006 - September 2011

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ARAMON, Montañas de Aragón (Ski resorts management company)

Zaragoza, Spain

December 2012 - June 2013

Logistics Consultant

- Developed the final year project of the Industrial Engineering degree "Analysis and improvement of the internal logistics network used in the ski resorts owned by Aramon"
- Quantified the costs of the movements of materials for maintenance and workers inside the ski resorts in terms of fuel and time spent by the employees
- Designed an optimum logistics network inside the ski resorts and several measures focused on improving the control over the movements of the workers
- Proposed the project to the technical management of the company and established certain measures in the maintenance management system of the company

ARAGOFAR (Distribution of pharmaceutical products company) Logistics Consultant

Zaragoza, Spain October 2012 - January 2013

- Developed a project in ARAGOFAR, entitled "Proposal for improvement of an automated system in a pharmaceutical distributor"
- Identified the bottleneck in the distribution chain, which were producing delays in the distribution
- Developed a proposal for improvement in the process, based on the allocation of overflow channels in the conflicting points
- Delivered training sessions to the employees about the new measures to be implemented

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

English: Fluent, Cambridge Advanced Certificate

French: Advanced, six years at L'institut Français de Saragosse

OTHER INTERESTING INFORMATION

Hobbies: Classic novels, jazz and soul music, free ride ski, hiking

Software: Proficient in Microsoft Office (Windows and Macintosh). Ability to work with programs such

as SolidWorks, Photoshop, Illustrator, Matlab, Minitab, Ansys.

Living experience: Exchanges in Cork, Ireland and Edinburgh and London, UK

Driving License: B/A2